adelphi.edu 2019-04-26

# GDPR Privacy Notice | Adelphi University

Adelphi University respects your privacy, but we occasionally will ask you to provide us with some information about you. For example, if you want to come to one of our events, we might ask for your name and your email address. We also record basic information about the use of our networks so that we are better equipped to fix problems.

If we have information about you, we will strive to protect it. Any information you give us will only be used for its intended purpose, and we won’t sell it to others. If we need it for something else, we’ll ask for your consent. 

If you suspect that we have made a mistake, please tell us and we’ll address your concerns. If you believe that we have information that we shouldn’t have, please tell us, and we’ll delete it. We cannot always do that because of other rules and regulations, but if that’s the case, we’ll tell you.

Adelphi University complies with the European General Data Privacy Regulation (GDPR). We are serious about your privacy and cybersecurity. If you have questions, please contact us at [privacy@adelphi.edu](mailto:privacy@adelphi.edu).

* * *

Questions and Answers

### What is the GDPR?

The GDPR is the General Data Privacy Protection Regulation. It is issued by the European Union, and it applies to all residents of the EU, regardless of the location of that data.

### What is protected by the GDPR?

The GDPR protects personal information of residents of the European Union. Under the GDPR, personal information is any information that relates to a person.

### Who should I contact if I have questions about my GDPR rights at Adelphi?

Email [privacy@adelphi.edu](mailto:privacy@adelphi.edu) and tell us what your questions are. We’ll make sure that your inquiry gets directed to the right person.

### Do you use web cookies?

Yes, we do use cookies to analyze how our websites are used. However, you can disable cookies in your web browser at any time, and everything will work fine. We only keep the cookie data for a short period of time. After that, we get rid of the individual records.

### Does the GDPR apply to me?

If you are a resident of the European Union, the GDPR will apply to you on or after May 25, 2018.

### What rights does the GDPR give me?

The GDPR gives all residents of the European Union the right to inspect, annotate, or request deletion of personal identity information. In addition, it expects us to design our systems in a way that we respect your privacy and that we protect any information we have about you.

### Does Adelphi collect personal information?

Yes, we do. The nature of that information varies. For example, if you are a student, we will keep your name, the classes you took or are planning to take, your grades, etc. In general, we try to keep the personal information we collect to a minimum.

### Why do you collect personal information?

We collect personal information to provide educational services to students, to maintain contact with alumni and friends of the University, and to keep you safe. We may also use some of that information to provide you with extra information about Adelphi University, but you can tell us to stop doing that at any time.

### Will you sell my personal information to others?

No.

### If GDPR applies to me, can I ask Adelphi for any information about me?

Yes, you can. However, there may be other laws and regulations that limit what we are allowed to disclose. When in doubt, contact us.

### Can I ask Adelphi to remove any information about me if I’m covered by the GDPR?

It depends. Some information we record is subject to other laws and regulations. For example, we will not honor requests to delete transcript information. When in doubt, contact us.

### How long is information retained?

If you give us information, we may not keep it. Information we don’t need will be securely removed. It is hard to say exactly after how long, since that depends on the nature of the information and on laws and regulations. When in doubt, ask us.

* * *

#### For more information, please contact:

**Privacy at Adelphi University**  
e – [privacy@adelphi.edu](mailto:privacy@adelphi.edu)
